<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Learning_Planning]]></title><description><![CDATA[Obsidian digital garden]]></description><link>http://github.com/dylang/node-rss</link><image><url>lib/media/favicon.png</url><title>Learning_Planning</title><link></link></image><generator>Webpage HTML Export plugin for Obsidian</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 03:57:14 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="lib/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 03:57:14 GMT</pubDate><ttl>60</ttl><dc:creator></dc:creator><item><title><![CDATA[Lamp Blog]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>This is my first blog so hopefully it's engaging and interesting enough. So, why did I make this lamp? When people ask me why I make stuff, I tend to answer "Why not?" But in this case I had good reason to be making it. My current desk lamp at the time was on the fritz and I'd had the idea for a while to make a lamp that helps me wake up for early mornings. The idea is to have this lamp slowly increase brightness to emulate a sunrise on days when I need to wake up before the sun has risen.<br>This is a blog about the design and prototyping of a lamp I made in order to help me get up for early morning classes.<br>Simply from a few tests without the lamp, I feel like it is actually helping considerably. On days without the lamp, I wake up to just my alarm blaring and I struggle to even comprehend how to snooze it. But with the lamp, I wake up much more easily and feeling more refreshed.<br>Keeping in mind, I only use the lamp for days I have to wake up before the sun has also woken up.<br><br>Started with the base where the boards are mounted<br>
First modeled the bounds of the boards<br><br>For the sake of efficiency and just to get some practice, I decided to go with a constant current supply rather than the typically used current limiting resistor design<br><br>Initially I'd started writing the software for the STM32 completely from scratch in bare metal C with no help libraries (I was not sane). The first version of the lamp which I used for a year used these handwritten libraries. I then switched to using libopencm3 for a more robust and WAY faster development (I'm still not sane, I know).<br>Talk about terminal interface as well<br><br>Used a very large heavy iron tip for large thermal mass (easier to work with the big copper heatsink)<br>
Flattened spots on wire heatsink for each led<br>
Made sure flattened spots all point in same direction<br>
Applied some solder to back of each led where it would normally attach to a heatsink<br><br>RTC battery<br>
brightness potentiometer]]></description><link>lamp-blog.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Lamp Blog.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 03:57:06 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>